Inventory of the Mary C. Rixford papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Italian materials, 1915, 1917 (Box-folder 2: 2)
  - Why Italy Is With the Allies, Anthony Hope, London, Richard Clay and Sons, Ltd., 1917
- Russian materials, 1914 (Box-folder 2: 3)
  - Documents Respecting the Negotiations Preceding the War, Published by the Russian Government, presented to both Houses of Parliament by Command of His Majesty, October 1914, London, printed under the authority of His Majesty's Stationery Office by Harrison and Sons
  - Russia: The Psychology of a Nation, by Paul Vinogradoff, F.B.A., Corpus Professor of Jurisprudence in the University of Oxford, sometime Professor of History in the University of Moscow, Oxford Pamphlets, Oxford University Press, Humphrey Milford, London, 1914.
- Anti-German materials, 1914-1918 (Box 2)
  - Evidence and Documents Laid before the Committee on Alleged German Outrages, Being on Appendix to the report of the Committee appointed by His Britannic Majesty's Government and presided over by the Right Hon. Viscount Bryce, O.M., Formerly British Ambassador to Washington. Contains details outrages on civil population in Belgium and France; the use of civilians as screen' offences against combatants; firing on hospitals, stretcher bearers, etc.; extracts from diaries and papers of German soldiers; proclamations by German Army authorities; some articles of the Hague convention concerning the laws and customs of war; facsimiles of papers found on German soldiers. Published by the Macmillan Company, New York for his Majesty's stationery Office, London, circa 1915
  - The Fallacy of the German State Philosophy, George W. Crile, New York, Doubleday, Page and Company, 1918
  - Failure of German Compulsory Health Insurance – A War Revelation, by Frederick L. Hoffman, LL.D., Third Vice-Presidents and Statistician, the Prudential Insurance Company of America, Newark, New Jersey, An address delivered at the Twelfth Annual Meeting of the Association of Life Insurance Presidents At New York, December 6, 1918
  - General Von Bissing's Testament: A Study in German Ideas, T. Fisher Unwin Ltd., London, circa 1917
  - German Atrocities: from German Evidence, by Joseph Bédier, Professor at the Collège de France, translated by Bernard Harrison, Librairie Armand Colin, Paris, circa 1917.
    Studies and Documents of the War series
  - The German Idea of Peace Terms, J. M. Robertson, Hodder and Stoughton, London, New York, Toronto, circa 1917
  - The German Note and The Reply of The Allies, T. Fisher Unwin, Ltd., 1917
  - The German Pirate: His Methods and Record, by Ajax, George H. Doran Company, Publishers, New York, circa 1917
  - Germany's Food Supply, W. J. Ashley, reprinted from The Quarterly Review, October, 1915, London, Jas. Truscott and Son, Ltd., 1916
  - The Horrors of Aleppo Seen by a German Eyewitness (A word to Germany's Accredited Representatives by Dr. Martin Niepage, Higher Grade Teacher in the German Technical School at Aleppo, at present at Wernigerode), T. Fisher Unwin Ltd., London, 1915
  - How Germany Seeks to Justify Her Atrocities, by Joseph Bédier, Professor at the Collège de France, translated by J. S., Librairie Armand Colin, Paris, circa 1917.
  - The New German Empire: A Study of German War Aims From German Sources, reprinted from The Round Table, March 17, 1917, Hodder and Stoughton, London, New York, Toronto
  - Report of The Committee on Alleged German Outrages Appointed by His Britannic Majesty's Government and presided over by The Right Hon. Viscount Bryce, O. M. formerly British Ambassador at Washington, Committee of Alleged German Outrages, published by Macmillan and Company, New York, for His Majesty's Stationery office, London, 1914
  - Revelations By an Ex-Director of Krupp's, Dr. Muhlom's Memorandum and His Letter to Herr von Bethmann-Hollweg, New York, George H. Doran Company, 1917
- Indian materials, 1915-1917 (Box 2: 4)
  - Loyal India: An Interview With Lord Harding of Penshurst, Ex-Viceroy and Governor-General of India. The London Correspondent of The New York Times, London, Sir Joseph Causton and Sons, Limited, 1916
  - Some American Opinions on the Indian Empire: Theodore Roosevelt, William Howard Taft, Franklin E. Jeffreys, Admiral Goodrich, James Mascarene Hubbard, John P. Jones, and others. T. Fisher Unwin, Ltd., London, circa 1917
  - Some Facts About India: Interview With Lord Islington During November, 1916, Robert Sloss, London, Burrup, Mathieson and Sprague, Ltd., 1917
  - A Suspect Manifesto and a Neutral Expert (Manifesto of the Indian National Party), 1915
  - The Verdict of India, Mancherjee M. Bhownaggree, Hodder and Stoughton, London, New York, Toronto, 1916
- Romanian materials, 1915-1916 (Box 2: 5)
  - Greater Rumania: A Study In National Ideas, D. Mitrany, Hodder and Stoughton, London, New York, Toronto, circa 1916
  - Justice Of Rumania's Cause, A. W. Leeper, Hodder and Stoughton, London, New York, Toronto, circa 1916
  - Policy Of National Instinct, a speech delivered by M. Take Jonesco in the Romanian Chamber of Deputies during the sitting of the 16th and 17th December, 1915
- Turkish materials, 1917 (Box 2: 6)
  - Ottoman Domination, reprinted from The Round Table, T. Fisher Unwin, Ltd., London, 1917
  - Turkey: A Past and a Future, A. J. Toynbee, New York, George H. Doran Company, circa 1917
- Irish materials, 1916-1917 (Box 2: 7)
  - Canada to Ireland: The Visit of the "Duchess of Connaught's Own." A. M. Drysdale, T. Fisher Unwin, Ltd., London, 1917
  - Voice of Ireland, Being an Interview with John Redmond, M.P., and Some Message from Representative Irishmen Regarding the Sinn Fein Rebellion, Thomas Nelson and Sons, London, 1916
- Materials of other countries, 1915-1918 (Box 2)
  - Armenian Atrocities: The Murder of a Nation, by Arnold J. Toynbee, with a speech delivered by Lord Bryce in the House of Lords, Hodder and Stoughton, London, New York, Toronto, 1915
  - Commercial Future of Baghdad, London, The Complete Press, 1917
  - Czecho-Slovaks: An Oppressed Nationality, by Lewis B. Namier, Hodder and Stoughton, London, New York, Toronto, circa 1916
  - Destruction of Poland: A Study in German Efficiency, by Arnold J. Toynbee, T. Fisher Unwin, Ltd., London, circa 1917
  - King of Hedjas and Arab Independence, with a facsimile of the proclamation of June 27, 1916. London, Hayman, Christy and Lilly, Ltd., 1917
  - League of Nations, by Viscount Grey of Fallodon, K.C., New York, George H. Doran Company, 1918
  - Palestine: The Organ of the British Palestine Committee. Bulletin, Vol. II, No. 16, November 24th, 1917
- Photocopies of covers, undated (Box 2: 8)